mobilemarketingmagazine.com 2018-10-20

# Privacy Policy | Mobile Marketing Magazine

**Commitment to privacy**  
This notice applies to all personal data collected by us in respect of our events and services, and collected or submitted on the Mobilemarketingmagazine.com website, or the website of our sister sites, specifically www.masterclassing.com and www.mobilemarketingsummits.com. The said websites are operated by Masterclassing Limited.

We ask that you read this privacy notice carefully as it contains important information on who we are, how and why we collect, store, use and share personal information, your rights in relation to your personal information and on how to contact us and supervisory authorities in the event you have a complaint.

 **Who we are**  
Masterclassing Ltd, which publishes Mobile Marketing Magazine, collects, uses and is responsible for certain personal information about you. When we do so we are regulated under the General Data Protection Regulation which applies across the European Union (including in the United Kingdom) and we are responsible as ‘controller’ of that personal information for the purposes of those laws.

The personal information we collect and use1. Information collected by usIn the course of hosting our events programme, whitepaper research service, awards programme and webinar series, we collect the following personal information when you provide it to us:  
• Name  
• Job title  
• Company  
• Phone number  
• Email address  
• Twitter handle

2\. Information collected from other sources

We also collect personal information from other sources as follows:  
• Sources of data in the public domain  
• Social networks  
• Conferences and seminars

We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

Please also note that we do not knowingly collect data relating to children. 

**How we use your personal information**  
We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:  
• Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.  
• Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.  
• Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

We use your personal information as follows:

**Purpose/Activity**

| 

**Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest**  
  
---|---  
  
To process and deliver any contract you have with us for the sale of our products, services or publications to you

| 

Performance of a contract with you  
  
To provide you with information you have requested from us, respond to enquiries or requests from you and communicate with you in relation to those enquiries or requests

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (carrying out activities in the course of our business in response to customer enquiries or requests)  
  
To administer and protect our business and our website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data). 

| 

(a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise)

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To enable you to give feedback or complete a survey

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business)  
  
To provide you with information regarding our events, services and publications, to invite you to our events, and to invite you to access our services and publications - and in each case to process your registration/attendance/access

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)  
  
IN RESPECT OF MOBILE MARKETING MAGAZINE ONLY – To circulate our newsletter to you

| 

Your consent  
  
To share your registration details with third parties, as further described below.

| 

Your consent  
  
**Opting out**  
You can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or by [contacting us](mailto:john@masterclassing.com) at any time. 

Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data that we process and use on a different lawful basis, or in respect of which you continue to consent to us processing.

 **Our Website - Cookies**  
We use cookies on our website, which may collect personal data. We may publish a separate Cookie Policy on our website to provide more information about the cookies we use. You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of our website may become inaccessible or not function properly. 

 **Our Website - Third-party links**  
Our website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

 **Suppliers**  
If you are a supplier to us, you will be asked to supply certain personal data to us and we will process that personal data for the purposes of the contract that you and we enter into for the supply of your products/services.

 **Who we share your personal information with**  
We will share the registration details that you provide to us either on registration for an event, upon downloading our research Whitepapers, or on participating in our webinars (“Your Details”) with the digital partners who are sponsoring the event you are attending, or the research partner of the Whitepaper you download, or the presenting partner of the webinar you participate in, as applicable. 

Attendance at our events, downloading our Whitepapers and participating in our webinars is free of charge because the sponsors of the event, the research partner of the Whitepaper, or the presenting partners of the webinar (the “Digital Partners”) have funded the event/Whitepaper/webinar and made it possible. Details of the Digital Partners are shown on the relevant registration page on our website. In return, we will provide Your Details to our Digital Partners so they can send marketing communications to you. This may involve a transfer of your personal data outside the EU. Nevertheless, the Digital Partners will have to comply with applicable data protection legislation. 

We require your express consent to this as a condition of registration, because our events, research papers and webinars would not be possible on a free-to-access basis without this requirement. We consider that the privacy impact upon you is minimal, and is off-set by the benefits of being able to attend/access our events, research papers and webinars free of charge.

If you do not consent to the passing of Your Details to our Digital Partners (by ticking the box on our website registration form), you will not be able to proceed to register for, or attend/access, our events, research papers and webinars. 

We may also share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table above.  
• Service providers (acting as processors) who provide services to us, including for example IT service providers;   
• Professional advisers (acting as processors or joint controllers) including bankers, lawyers, accountants and insurers who provide banking, consultancy, legal, insurance and accounting services.  
• HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities (acting as processors or joint controllers) who may require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.

We may make your personal data available to our sister company, Masterclassing Inc, who are based in the USA. The USA does not have the same data protection laws as the United Kingdom and EEA. Any such transfer of your personal information will be subject to the European Commission approved standard data protection clauses as permitted under Article 46(2)(d) of the General Data Protection Regulation that are designed to help safeguard your privacy rights and give you remedies in the unlikely event of a misuse of your personal information.

We will not share your personal information with any other third party.

 **Whether information has to be provided by you, and if so why**  
The provision of name, company, job title, email address and telephone number is required from you to enable us to process your registration at one of our service offerings – events, whitepapers, awards, webinars. We will inform you at the point of collecting information from you, whether you are required to provide the information to us. If you do not provide the information we ask for, we may not be able to make our events, products or services available to you.

 **How long your personal information will be kept**  
We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. 

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

By law we have to keep basic information about our customers for seven years after they cease being customers, for tax purposes.We keep personal data relating to our suppliers for longer, as it is in both our interests and theirs that they remain on our system and potentially available for work from us.

 **Your rights**  
Under the General Data Protection Regulation you have a number of important rights free of charge. In summary, those include rights to:  
• Fair processing of information and transparency over how we use your use personal information  
• Access to your personal information• require us to correct any mistakes in your information which we hold  
• Require the erasure of personal information concerning you in certain situations  
• Receive the personal information concerning you which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have the right to transmit those data to a third party in certain situations  
• Object at any time to processing of personal information concerning you for direct marketing  
• Object to decisions being taken by automated means which produce legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affect you• object in certain other situations to our continued processing of your personal information  
• Otherwise restrict our processing of your personal information in certain circumstances

For further information on each of those rights, including the circumstances in which they apply, see the Guidance from the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) on individuals rights under the General Data Protection Regulation.

If you would like to exercise any of those rights, please:  
• Email, call or write to our Data Protection Officer, John Owen, john@masterclassing.com, +44-7769-674824, Masterclassing Ltd, 57-61 Charterhouse Street, London, EC1M 6HA  
• If you would like to unsubscribe from any email you can also click on the ‘unsubscribe’ link at the bottom of the emails. It may take up to 10 days for this to take place. 

 **Keeping your personal information secure**  
We have appropriate security measures in place to prevent personal information from being accidentally lost, or used or accessed in an unauthorised way. We limit access to your personal information to those who have a genuine business need to know it. Those processing your information will do so only in an authorised manner and are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We also have procedures in place to deal with any suspected data security breach. We will notify you and any applicable regulator of a suspected data security breach where we are legally required to do so.

 **How to complain**  
We hope that we can resolve any query or concern you raise about our use of your information. The General Data Protection Regulation also gives you right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the European Union (or European Economic Area) state where you work, normally live or where any alleged infringement of data protection laws occurred. The supervisory authority in the UK is the Information Commissioner who may be contacted at https://ico.org.uk/concerns/ or telephone: [0303 123 1113].

Changes to this privacy noticeThis privacy notice was published on May 24, 2018.

We may change this privacy notice from time to time, when we do we will update the privacy notice on our website.

 **How to contact us**  
Please contact John Owen, our Co-Founder and Data Protection Officer, if you have any questions about this privacy notice or the information we hold about you.If you wish to contact our Data Protection Officer, please send an email to john@masterclassing.com, write to Masterclassing Ltd, 57-61 Charterhouse Street, London, EC1M 6HA or call +44-7769-674824.
